

LOUIS EYOMA

0814 619 3371 | louiseyoma@yahoo.com Cross River, Nigeria.

Education

2021-2023

Msc in Software Engineering | Italy

Free University of Bozen Bolzano

2015

BSc in Computer Engineering | Ghana Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology

Certifications & Licenses

AWS Cloud Developer, 2020

https://coursera.org/share/bafd3e8b23cd5 2a305a6643655f276b7

Skills

- Full Stack Web Application Development
- Software Test Engineering
- Linux Server Administration
- Leadership
- Technical Writing
- Public Speaking
- Communication in English

Technologies

- Python (Diango)
- Java (Spring Boot)
- HTML and Tailwind CSS
- NodeJs
- Typescript and Javascript
- Selenium and Cypress
- NextIs
- Jenkins
- AWS
- Docker

Professional Summary

I am a Software Engineering research student at the Free University of Bozen Bolzano. Over the past half decade, I have been studying and developing software solutions for information and embedded systems. I aspire to heal the Nigerian Educational system through technology, and contribute effectively to the development of tech startups in Nigeria.

Work History

01/2021 - Current

Crestmonds | Dartford, England

Lead Software Developer

- •Developed the frontend of the crestcompare application using nextis
- Built APIs for the crestlearn learning platform using python(Django) and mysql.
- Independently developed a video library application for learners.
- Setup pipelines for continuous integration and continuous delivery using jenkins.
- Administration of linux servers
- Assist the scrum team with product discovery activities like empathy mapping, user stories and acceptance criterias, use case and user flow diagrams.

01/2018 - Current

School of Health Info. Mgt. UCTH | Cross River, Nigeria Lecturer

- Teach Computer Programming
- Teach how to use computer packages (SPSS, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Word, Microsoft Powerpoint and District Health Information Systems)
- Supervised various academic projects carried out by students.
- Maintain the school's IT infrastructure.
- Develop and Manage all Inhouse software applications.

01/2019 - 03/2020

Chatscrum Inc | Maryland, USA

Remote Software Developer

- Implementation of a scrum board application that can be used by a scrum team to manage their product backlog..
- Implementation of a realtime chat application using AWS Lambda, websocket and API Gateway.

01/2019 - 03/2020

Linuxjobber Inc | Maryland, USA

Remote Software Engineer and Tutor

- Manual testing and writing of test automation scripts using selenium to support regression testing.
- Full Stack application developer with java, python, html, css, javascript and mysql.
- Created contents for lab sessions, reading materials and made tutorial videos for various courses including GoLang, Python, Django, javafx, Angular, AWS RDS, AWS IAM, AWS EC2, AWS VPC, AWS S3, AWS cloudformation, Kubernetes and Docker.
- Facilitated daily standup meetings and supervised tasks performed by other team members.